In this concept, we'll go over some of
在这一部分 我们将介绍运用到注意力机制的
the computer vision applications and tasks that attention empowers.
一些计算机视觉应用和任务
In the text below the video,
在视频下方的文本中
we'll link to a number of papers in case you want to go
我们给出了多篇论文的链接
deeper into any specific application or task.
方便你深入了解任何特定应用或任务
In this video, we'll focus on image captioning and
在此视频中 我们将重点讲解图像说明
one of the key papers from 2016 titled,
并介绍 2016 年的一篇重要论文
"Show, Attend and Tell."
“Show, Attend and Tell.”
This paper presented a model that achieved the state of
这篇论文中介绍的模型
the art performance in caption generation in a number of datasets.
在大量数据集中针对说明生成都取得了先进的效果
For example, when presented with an image like this,
例如 对于这张图像
the generated caption was,
模型生成的说明是
"A woman is throwing a frisbee in a park."
“A woman is throwing a frisbee in a park.”
When presented with an image like this,
对于这张图像
the generated caption was,
生成的说明是
"A giraffe standing in a forest with trees in the background."
“A giraffe standing in a forest with trees in the background.”
Models like these are trained on a dataset like the MS Coco,
这样的模型是用 MS Coco 等数据集训练的
which has a set of about 200,000 images,
该数据集有大约 200,000 张图像
each with five captions written by people.
每个图像都由人工编写了 5 个说明
This is sourced through something like Amazon's Mechanical Turk Service.
这些说明是通过亚马逊的 Mechanical Turk Service 获得的
For example, this image from the dataset has
例如 数据集中的这张图像
these five captions as it's
具有这五个说明标签
labels and this is the dataset that we used to train a model like this.
我们使用这个数据集训练这样的模型
If we look under the hood,
如果研究一下背后原理的话
the model is very similar to the sequence to
会发现该模型和我们之前看到的
sequence models we've looked at earlier in the lesson.
序列到序列模型很相似
In this case, the model takes the image as an input to it's encoder,
在这种情形下 模型将图像作为编码器的输入
the encoder generates a context,
编码器生成语境
passes it to the decoder.
将语境传递给解码器
The decoder then proceeds to output a caption.
解码器然后做出处理并生成说明
The model generates the caption sequentially and uses attention to
模型按顺序生成说明
focus on the appropriate place of the image as it generates each word of the caption.
在生成说明的每个单词时侧重于图像的相应部分
For example, when presented with this image,
例如 对于这个图像
in the first step,
在第一步
the trained model focuses on this region.
训练模型侧重于这个区域
So, this is the thumbnail of this image.
这是该图像的缩略图
The white areas is where the model is paying the most attention right now.
模型现在重点查看的是白色区域
So, we can see that it's mainly focused on the wings.
可以看出 它主要关注的是翅膀
It then outputs the first element in the output sequence or the caption,
然后输出输出序列（说明）中的第一个元素
which is the word "a."
即单词“a”
The next step at the decoder,
解码器的下一步
it focuses on this region,
侧重于这个区域
so mainly the body of the bird as you see,
主要是小鸟的身体
and the output would be "bird",
输出单词“bird”
and then it expands it's focus area to this area
然后将聚焦区域扩展到小鸟周围的区域
around the bird to try to figure out what to describe next,
尝试查看下一步该描述什么
and the output at this step is "flying".
这一步的输出是“flying”
This goes on. We can see how it's attention.
一直持续下去
Right now is starting to radiate out of the bird
可以看出注意力现在开始从小鸟身上转移
and focus on things behind it or around it.
并侧重于小鸟背后或周围的事物
So, it's generating "a bird flying over a body of",
生成了“a bird flying over a body of”
and then the focus here completely sort of ignores the bird,
然后 焦点完全忽略小鸟
and trying to look at everywhere else in the image, "water."
尝试查看图像中的所有剩余区域 生成“water”
The first time I looked at something like this, image captioning specifically,
当我第一次看到图像说明这种应用时
it was mind-blowing to me,
简直被震撼了
but now, we have an idea of how it works.
现在知道原理了
The model here is made of an encoder and a decoder as we've mentioned.
正如之前提到的 这里的模型由编码器和解码器组成
The encoder in this case is
这里的编码器是一个卷积神经网络
a convolutional neural network that produces a set of feature vectors,
生成一组特征向量
each of which corresponds to a part of the image or a feature of the image.
每个向量对应于图像的某个部分 即图像的特征
To be more exact, the paper used
更准确地说 该论文使用了
a VGG net convolutional network trained on the Image net.
通过 ImageNet 进行训练的 VGG 卷积网络
The annotations were created from this feature map.
注释是用这个特征图创建的
This feature volume has dimensions of 14 x 14 x 512,
这个特征图的大小是 14 x 14 x 512
meaning that it has 512 features,
表明有 512 个特征
each of them has the dimensions of 14 x 14.
每个特征的大小是 14 x 14
To create our annotation vector,
要创建注释向量
we need to flatten each feature,
我们需要扁平化每个特征
turning it from 14 x 14 to 196 x 1.
将其从 14 x 14 变成 196 x 1
So, this is simply reshaping the matrix.
也就是调整矩阵的形状
After we reshape it to end up with a matrix of 196 x 512.
调整形状后 变成 196 x 512 的矩阵
So, we have 512 features,
有 512 个特征
each one of them is a vector of 196 numbers.
每个特征都是有 196 个数字的向量
So, this is our context vector.
这是语境向量
We can proceed to use it just like we've used the context vector in the previous videos,
可以像在之前的视频中一样使用这个语境向量
where we score each of these features and then we merge
对每个特征评分 然后合并结果
them to produce our attention context vector.
生成注意力语境向量
The decoder is a recurrent neural network,
解码器是一个循环神经网络
which uses attention to focus on the appropriate annotation vector at each time step.
它使用注意力在每个时间步侧重于相应的注释
We plug this into the attention process we've
将这个代入之前讲解的注意力流程中
outlined before and that's our image captioning model.
这就是我们的图像说明模型
Be sure to check the text below the video for
请务必阅读视频下方的文本
some very exciting applications in computer vision for attention.
了解注意力在计算机视觉中的一些精彩应用